"Cancer Cell II (Part II)."
All right, how should we go about this?
Where should the first slash go?
Harmful bacteria.
Pathogenic E. coli, Staphylococci, Clostridium and the like
cause proteins to degrade and produce toxic by-products.
They are detrimental to the human body in various ways.
Impressive! You harmful bacteria are the entertainers of evil!
Incredible! Letting him know what you're about to do to him...
How insanely cruel!
How about slamming him against the wall with your tentacles next?
Opportunistic pathogens.
Bacteroides, non-pathogenic E. coli, Eubacterium and the like
are all bacteria which do neither good nor harm.
They make up roughly 70 percent of the bacteria in the intestines.
Shut up, opportunistic pathogens!
I'm trying to come up with the most artistic way of tormenting this cell in the name of evil!
So, don't disturb me!
So brutal! I'm getting goosebumps!
Well, not that I can blame you opportunistic bacteria
for being enthralled by our cool evil souls.
Watch and learn!
Woo-hoo!
Hey there, Mr. President!
You're so cool!
All right, what should I do?
Should I start dismembering you from the fingertips?
Okay, I've got it.
Your eyes!
Damn!
White Blood Cells!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Cell boy!
You've got a lot of nerve, rampaging around the biggest immune system in the body!
It's punishment time, you lousy germs!
Gut immunity.
The ability to fight off and eliminate bacteria and viruses invading the body
is called "immunity."
The digestive tract acts as a barrier to protect against infection
and is said to be home to upward of 50 percent of the body's immune system.
Wh-What should we do, Harmful Bacterium?
Hold your ground! So unsightly!
Huh! We've still got...
...the edge in sheer numbers!
What the... Where'd all these come from?
This staggering number of opportunistic bacteria are all my allies!
In an environment where the harmful bacteria hold sway...
...you should be mortified that you were ever rash enough to show your idiotic faces
even for a second!
Numbers! The symbol of power!
There is no higher aesthetic for us bacteria than to win by numbers!
Nyuuu!
A-Are those good bacteria?
Good bacteria.
Lactic acid bacterium, Lactobacillus gasseri, Lactobacillus bifidus and the like
work to boost immunity and to stimulate intestinal activity.
Their actions are beneficial for the human body's health.
Nyuuu!
How can there be so much good bacteria?
Hey, opportunistic bacteria!
What are you doing? Get rid of them already—
Huh?
Quit nagging, will you? The environment's changed, all right?
Right! What do you mean by "artistic" and "cool evil"?
Don't be full of yourselves! How troublesome!
From now on, it will be the Age of Good Bacteria!
It's time for us to find our place among the beautiful and wholesome bacteria!
The nature of opportunistic pathogens.
They ally themselves with whichever bacteria, good or harmful, has the upper hand.
So... So anyway...
...let's all get along and be friends, everyone!
Not by a long shot.
All you germs guilty of unlawful entry, get the cell out!
We should feel a little safer here, huh?
Oh look, Big Sister!
Huh?
Wait, something's changed?
It's easier to breathe!
Yeah!
Come to think of it...
This is toxic gas from the harmful bacteria that live in the intestines.
The bacterial balance in the gut must be off, and the harmful bacteria seem to be predominant.
This is bound to cause some harmful effects.
I wonder if White Blood Cell is all right.
Memory T! NK!
Don't worry.
I'm not planning to kill them.
There!
Stop!
Knock it off!
Cancer Cell!
Why? Why won't you fight me? Fight me!
I don't want to.
Because what I like about you is how self-contradictory you are.
You're the same as me, writhing within your preordained destiny.
I don't want to kill a friend.
That's right. Unlike you...
...I detest you!
Because you called me "a goddamn bug"!
Stop! Isn't that enough?
Step away from Memory T!
I can't tell you how glad I am that I brought the three of you here.
I like you, White Blood Cell!
I could sit and chat with you about all kinds of things.
As for Memory T and NK, I hate you both!
What wouldn't I give to demolish everything you hold dear?
I can turn those emotions into energy
and acquire that power way sooner than I thought!
If I divide once, it'll be double.
Divide again, and I can double again!
A mere thirty divisions will result...
...in more than a billion of my friends.
Try and stop me if you can...
...my hard-working Immune Cells.
It's too soon for a victory lap.
I still have my...
...trump card left.
Bursting at the seams with my memories...
The ultimate secret technique!
Memory T?
That moron... What in the world is he...
And it's called...
The T Cell Ultimate Secret Technique... "Perforin Cannon Punch"!
"T Cell Per—" What?
Huh?
"T..." Huh?
What was that?
"T Cell Puerile Cretin Panties"?
That's "T Cell Perforin Cannon Punch"!
Secret technique?
The thymus.
The lymphoid organ where Precursor T Cells are differentiated
and then mature into full-fledged T Cells.
Hey, you were hopeless a little while ago, but these days you're on fire!
That was just dumb luck.
But I'm going to keep grinding away and hone my skills. You'll see.
Actually, the way you're going... Oh, but I shouldn't say it...
Oh come on, spit it out!
Well... See... I'm thinking that a cell of your caliber
just might be able to master that ultimate secret technique.
Ultimate secret technique?
Yeah. It's called the "T Cell Ultimate Secret Technique"...
Perforin... Cannon Punch!
Perforin.
A chemical released by Killer T Cells upon attacking infected cells.
It's a legendary move that can only be unleashed
when a T Cell's urge to protect the world intensifies to its maximum peak inside him.
They say that whoever's on the receiving end of its devastating force and impact
ends up getting blasted away like they were smashed with a massive fist.
"Ultimate Secret Technique"...
Emotions... Making your fist... Massive...
The T Cell Ultimate Secret Technique...
Perf... Perforin Cannon Punch!
Whoops, I mangled it.
Oh jeez, he's really practicing it!
Who would've thought he'd swallow a dumbass story like that?
Like that kind of move even exists!
Perforin C-Cannon Panty!
Oh crap, my arm cramped up!
What are those guys doing?
They just want to reassure themselves by looking down on others. What a pair of morons.
You're not going to get your way.
Oh?
Eat this!
T Cell...
...Perforin Cannon Punch!
T Cell Perforin Cannon Punch!
It really...
...worked!
Wh-Wh-What the cell was that baffling move just now?
Regulatory... Regulatory T Cell!
You're supposed to suppress his attacks!
Why did you just dodge now?
It's your job to protect me—
I should've known better.
I seem to have misperceived you.
Huh?
You are not a cell that warrants protection.
Now, at last, I've realized my error.
Upon closer inspection, I can see...
...that you're not a cell...
...but rather a "cll."
That's what convinced you?
Regulatory T Cell's role.
Once she's perceived a change in a Cancer Cell,
Regulatory T Cell no longer recognizes it as a cell to be protected.
Because I'm a "cll," not a "cell"?
Is that it?
That's correct.
And I'm not a cell that warrants protection, huh?
So, that means you're no longer on my side, right?
Well, I guess that's fine by me.
If that's what you think, Regulatory T Cell, then that's fine by me.
But...
...you're going to have to stay out of my way!
I told you! I know all your tricks!
Nailed it!
And I told you, remember?
Slashing me does no good!
Stop making me repeat myself!
I'm telling you, I know all your tricks! Didn't you hear—
What's wrong? I thought you knew all my tricks!
Whoa! Whoa!
All right, let's finish this now, Immune Cells.
Damn!
I'll kill you!
Crap! Damn, you're hard!
Won't be long now.
This is...
...the end!
The new world...
Now we can be free!
And...
It's over now.
The only thing that's over is you!
You goddamn bug!
You miserable Cancer Cell!
Die!
I'm telling you, you can slash me, you can stab me, and I won't die.
My wings! Wh-Why?
I can't maintain my strength!
I'm no longer getting a boost?
But why?
It looks like the intestinal environment's changed,
so now the toxins from the harmful bacteria that were empowering you are dwindling.
White Blood Cell—
I've been defeated.
So, I lose again, huh?
Oh well, that's fine.
I'd rather be killed by a friend than by someone I hate. This is way better.
See you... my gentle assassin... White...
...Blood... Cell...
All right, it's over!
You guys...
You've gotten so big!
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Lactic acid bacteria.
Good bacteria that work to support the health of the human body.
They have a variety of features.
Nyuuu?
I'm okay.
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Thank goodness, Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Nyuuu!
Hey, thanks for coming to save me!
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
The Cancer Cell has been vanquished!
The crisis is over!
It really worked.
Yes, it did.
Nyuuu!
Whoa! Amazing!
Just look at him repair the intestinal wall for us!
Nyuuu!
How lactic acid bacteria works.
Some lactic acid bacteria directly stimulate the Intestinal Epithelial Cells
to help maintain the intestinal tract's barrier functions.
Lactic Acid Bacterium, you're awesome!
Thanks to you guys, the intestinal environment's improving!
Nyuuu!
You did great, too, Cell boy!
Huh? Me?
Bringing those lactic acid bacteria back to their friends
helped to improve the intestinal environment.
It was you who rescued us. Thanks.
Jeez. Just once in my life, if someone would say...
..."Thank you for rescuing me!"
What wouldn't I give to hear those words?
You mean I...
I was able to help out, too?
Yeah!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Intestinal environment and immunity.
Three different types of bacteria reside in the intestines. Good, harmful and opportunistic.
The intestinal environment changes whenever there is a shift in the balance between them.
When the number of good bacteria increases, there's a boost in immunity.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Intestinal flora.
There are good, harmful and opportunistic bacteria residing in the intestinal tract,
comprising hundreds of billions of bacteria from hundreds of different species.
Because it looks like a flower bed of colonies of various plants in the intestinal tract,
it's called "intestinal flora."
So, this...
This is the world where you guys live, huh?
We're totally drenched.
Yeah.
Goodbye...
Lactic acid bacteria.
Oh! White Blood Cell! Thanks for your hard work!
Hey there!
Good work!
Thank goodness! So, you're all right!
Yeah! You, too!
Oh, I almost forgot!
I've been delivering nutrients, and I've gone all the way around...
And the apartment belonging to that cell in the pharynx...
You wouldn't believe what's happened to it!
Huh?
Look at this huge pile of missed delivery notices!
No food for me, then?
Maybe I'll send him a snack later.
And we'll do our best to get his nutrients delivered as soon as possible!
Right, try and do that, will you?
Hey, Senpai!
Time to get back to work!
Oh, okay!
All right, White Blood Cell...
If you'll excuse me...
Yeah! See ya around!
All right, Naive Cells, check this out!
In that moment, my punch will transform into...
...the T Cell Ultimate Secret Technique!
Perfavore Cannon Punch!
Whoops, mangled it a bit!
That just looks like a regular punch to me.
I know.
One more time!
Parfyorin Can...
This is the inside of a human body.
Roughly 37 trillion cells
are working energetically and with all their might again today.
Thank you for waiting!
Here's your oxygen for the day!