wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa
donna mainichi mo sutaato kitta nara
As we wake up every day, there's no time to waste, come on
tekipaki patapata tada hashiru dake sa
Gotta hurry, dash and scurry, all our work won't finish itself
sainan kara kikan saikou no seika
Keep on going when we fail, always pushing forward
wa boroboro yogoreta manma hitoiki tiitaimu
And giving it our all until at last we get a moment for tea time
otsukaresama wo kurikaeshite
And though our rest is short, we head on out once more
mata guuzen kimi ni aitai (aitai, aitai, aitai)
But I still hope that I'll see you again (again, again, again)
motto tsuyoku naru kara
'Cause I wanna get stronger again!
kyou mo nani ga attatte (nani ga attatte)
I wonder what'll go on today? (What'll go on today?)
hatarakunda tte (hatarakunda tte)
While we're out in the fray (While we're out in the fray)
minna de sou ganbare sou
Everybody go! (Yeah!) Do the best you can! (Yeah!)
ashita no heiwa danko genshu
So that we can have a peaceful future
shinjita michi (shinjita michi)
Doing what's in my sight (Doing what's in my sight)
tsukisusunde ike (tsukisusunde ike)
What I believe is right (What I believe is right)
hitori ja nai shinase wa shinai
No one left to cry, no one has to die
mirakuru shuudan Cells at Work
We're the greatest team, the Cells at Work
(minna chigatte) hitotsu no shigoto
(Though we're all different kinds) We have a single purpose
(minna atsumatte) hitotsu no shigoto
(When we all come gather 'round) We have a single purpose
saibou festa hataraku saibou
It's a fiesta, all about Cells at Work!
go, go, go, go, go, go! saa ikou! (go, go, go!)
Go, go, go, go, go, go, hey, let's go!
go, go, go, go, go, go! saa ikou!