I wonder what's wrong.
Since he had had that talk with NK,
things seem kind of tense.
Nyuuu!
I wonder what's bugging those two.
Nyuuu?
"Harmful Bacteria."
U-Um, excuse me, how much farther?
Oh, right.
We're almost there. See?
This is the large intestine.
The large intestine.
The organ that absorbs water
and minerals and produces feces.
Where the final stage
of digestion is performed.
The large intestine is about
1.5 meters in length
and can be divided into the cecum,
the colon and the rectum.
It is said that several hundred
different species of bacteria,
totaling one hundred trillion,
inhabit the large intestine.
Not looking good.
It's gone to ruin, all right.
Let's see.
White Blood Cell! Ordinary Cell!
Thank you for your--
good work--I just happened--
--Are you okay?
--to be delivering--
I-I can't breathe!
This is toxic gas from the harmful
bacteria that live in the intestines.
--"Toxic gas"?
The bacterial balance in the gut must be off,
and the harmful bacteria seem to be predominant.
This is bound to cause some harmful effects.
Is that right?
What a stink!
I-I'm going to take care
of this delivery right now!
You be careful, okay?
Let's see, this delivery's going to...
Everyone, please look this way!
Okay!
Roughly three types of bacteria
reside in the intestines.
First, the good bacteria
that are beneficial to the body...
Good bacteria.
Lactic acid bacterium, Lactobacillus gasseri,
Lactobacillus bifidus and the like
work to boost immunity
and to stimulate intestinal activity.
Next, the scary harmful bacteria
that wreak havoc on the body!
Harmful bacteria.
Pathogenic E. coli, Staphylococci,
Clostridium and the like
cause proteins to degrade
and produce toxic by-products.
Wasn't that scary?
Yeah!
Last but not least,
--Are you okay?
--neither good nor bad...
Opportunistic pathogens!
Opportunistic pathogens.
Bacteroides, non-pathogenic E. coli,
Eubacterium and the like
are all bacteria which do neither good nor harm.
They ally themselves with whichever bacteria,
good or harmful, has the upper hand.
Oh, so cute!
Look how many of them there are!
That was fun, wasn't it?
Do you think we can come back sometime?
I hope so!
Hey there!
Oh! Big Sister Red Blood Cell!
Hello, little Platelets!
Hello!
Are you touring this area?
Yes! Oh! This way, this way!
Go on! Take a look! It's really cute!
The intestines are said to be home
to approximately a hundred
trillion bacteria in all.
The body's health changes whenever
there's a shift in the balance between them.
Oh really?
Hey, so his friends are all here?
Yeah.
There are up to a hundred trillion bacteria
in the intestines, they say.
Wow! That many right here?
Then, we're sure to find them, right?
Yeah.
That'll be a relief.
He doesn't sound the least bit relieved.
I wonder what's up with him.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium, it won't be long now.
There are tons of your friends
right here, all right?
I bet you have some
awesome powers of your own!
Nyuuu!
--Hey, you need to pipe down!
--Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
--Hey! You don't want NK to catch on!
She's eagle-eyed, you know!
It's glaringly obvious, guys. So ridiculous!
Look, you two, I don't care what you do
as long as you're quiet.
I don't want him to know we're on the move.
Attention!
Squad Leader, please be careful!
We'll be close behind you
with the antigen presentation signal!
All right!
Now, I've fought with him once in the past.
And I'm going to use that experience today
to head to the front lines as a Memory T Cell
and finish off the enemy!
Memory T Cell.
Some Killer T Cells turn into Memory T Cells
so that they can be ready to attack
in case the same enemy reappears.
I'm sure you'll miss me,
but it's going to be okay!
I'll still be looking out for you
even as a Memory T!
Whether or not you'll be
up to the fight after losing me...
Nothing worries me more
as your squad leader.
After all, who else but me
has the inside track on his moves...
--...and the ability to land
the decisive blow...
--The squad leader sure looks thrilled.
--...and the ability to land
the decisive blow...
--He may be mistaking this for a promotion.
But I swear on this cap
that I'll fulfill my mission.
Though there's no guarantee that any of us
will be alive when we meet again.
So, I'll be waiting for you all in hell!
Squad Leader!
Man, you're in my way.
Killer T!
Wh-What the... This abrupt,
uncalled for violence is--
Oh my, I'm really sorry. My foot slipped.
NK!
I was wondering what all you passive
grunt cells were doing, milling around here.
Is it a farewell bash?
Or maybe you're rehearsing for a play?
How nonchalant!
I'm not sure you even remember who the enemy
is now that you're so complacent, Memory T Cell.
NK, what did I ever do to you?
NK! Stop provoking Killer T
so that he'll regain his confidence!
Shut up!
Neutrophil! Did I hear you call me "Killer T"?
Can't you see this cap of mine?
It's "Memory T" today!
--Memory...
Hey! There you go again,
mellowing out with an ordinary cell!
Keep that up and you won't even
be able to kill a lowly germ!
Nyuuu!
"Nyuuu"?
Th-That's not true!
It may seem to be true,
but actually, it's not true at all!
That's right! It's not true!
I'm a natural-born killing machine!
And now, I'm off to prepare for battle!
It's dangerous here,
so you should go somewhere safe!
Yep, yep!
Yeah! You'll only get in my way
when I battle that guy!
Nyuuu!
I hear something crying.
What are these guys, idiots?
U-Um, I just have a simple question.
Who's this guy you keep mentioning?
--A Cancer Cell.
C-Cancer Cell?
A-A-An enemy like that at large...
I-I-Isn't that dangerous?
Sure, it's dangerous.
I've got to head out right away
to crush him. So, Cell boy...
...we'll be going our separate ways now.
Huh?
It's time for me to get back to work.
I'm sorry I can't accompany you to the end.
Listen.
If you go down this road and take a left, you'll
reach the tip of the intestinal epithelium.
I'm sure you'll come into contact
with Lactic Acid Bacterium's friends there.
So, return the little guy,
then leave the large intestine
and make your way back to the pharynx.
Okay.
All right. Keep an eye on your surroundings
and watch your back.
You can do it, right?
Yeah.
Thanks!
Oh, hold up, White Blood Cell!
Can you tell me one thing before you go?
White Blood Cell, why did you protect us?
After all...
...you Immune Cells...
If it's for the sake of the body,
you kill bacteria and infected cells
who used to be your allies.
Killing them is your job, isn't it?
So, how come?
Nyuuu?
Huh?
Right. You're absolutely right.
It's my job to kill.
But... since all I ever do is kill...
Maybe that's why...
All right, see you!
Make sure you send him off right!
--Nyu-nyuuu! Nyu-nyuuu!
--Right!
Nyu-nyuuu!
This slimy mucin will keep out
any invading bacteria.
Let's get them set up
so they don't get breached.
That sounds close.
Yeah.
We'd better hurry!
H-Here it comes!
All right! The barrier's
holding up like a champ!
You just can't beat mucin for durability.
That was barely a blip on the radar, huh?
Hold up!
Oh no!
There's more on the way!
Let's get out of here!
This way, this way!
Sorry!
There you go!
Thanks, Big Sister!
I wanna ride piggyback!
Me, too!
Me, too! Piggyback!
Ouch!
Um, you see, you see... Um...
Um...
Everyone! Big Sister Red Blood Cell doesn't
know what to do, so you all need to line up!
Okay!
You're all going to ride?
Wh-What's that?
Whoa!
Excuse me! That section seems to be broken--
Is that going to hold up?
Oh, please don't worry about it.
It happens all the time.
Whaaat?
Lately, with the surge in harmful bacteria,
the intestines have been a mess!
We're totally at our wits' end!
I-I see that's it's been tough for you all.
Um, go straight here...
I hear there are tons of bacteria
on the other side of this wall.
Nyuuu?
It's almost time to say goodbye.
Nyuuu!
A lot of terrifying things happened,
but it sure was fun, Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Nyuuu!
See...
I never had anyone
to play with when I was a kid,
and I was bored out of my mind.
I was really lonely.
So, meeting you guys...
...and traveling all around
the body like this...
It was such a blast!
Nyuuu! Nyu-nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
I told you, it's no use!
Nyuuu?
No good!
The bacteria's attack is too devastating, and
it's only a matter of time before they invade!
Goblet Cell.
A mucous-secreting Immune Cell
that produces mucin.
Can also be found in the small intestine but
particularly abundant in the large intestine.
Hang in there, Goblet Cell!
Intestinal Epithelial Cell.
Absorbs nutrients and water.
Also builds mucous barriers to prevent excessive
immune responses toward Intestinal Cells.
Do you know how many billions, trillions
of bacteria there are beyond this wall?
It looks like they're in trouble.
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu!
We Intestinal Epithelial Cells have to hold
them off with this intestinal barrier!
Oh man! No way are we
getting there in time now!
I mean it, it's futile! Come back here!
--I-I'll help you!
--Don't give up!
"With burning hearts!
With a solid intestinal barrier!"
Isn't that our motto? We have to keep
fighting until we reach our limit!
And I'm telling you, this is our limit!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu...
There goes all the mucin we planted!
Huh?
So, this is the other side of the intestinal
wall that we've been striving to reach?
Now that we're here, it's nothing special.
Not a shred of style.
Who cares? We're going to turn it
into an oasis for us harmful bacteria!
Toward that end,
we're going to have to start
by eradicating all of the weeds!
Come on!
Wh-What's going on?
Uh, it looks like there's some kind of problem.
It happens all the time!
H-H-H-Huh?
These harmful bacteria sure are troublesome!
Oh, you guys should all make a run for it, too!
Whaaat?
Are you okay, Platelet?
Yes! I'm fine!
--Better get out of here now!
--It seems like we've been invaded by bacteria!
Everyone! Watch out, okay?
I can't see in front of me!
The path's going to narrow from this point.
All right, then I'll take the lead.
Don't ram into me, you klutz.
I didn't shove you that hard, you know.
Are you that narrow-minded?
Damn you! Can you be
more unsteady on your feet?
Just go the cell home!
You're only going to get in my way!
Oh, that's rich! Right back atcha!
You bumped into me first!
Oh yeah? Well, why are you tagging along,
you miserable loner?
I'll take being a loner any day!
Better than your band of spineless fools!
What did you say?
Didn't I tell you to stay away?
It was my long years of experience and intuition
that led me to determine that he was here!
You're following me!
Hey, how about not clobbering
each other before the battle?
All right! We'll be reaching
the residential area soon!
It'll be teeming with cells! It might be
unbearable for a social outcast like you!
Killer T, you might want to stop talking now--
Huh? "Killer T"?
Call me "Memory T"! Don't you see this cap?
All right, fine! Just be quiet!
There's no telling where
the enemy might be lurking!
He's right. Are you a moron or what?
Why are you only telling me off? Not fair!
Shush!
It looks like he's meeting us head-on this time.
Hey, NK!
Damn you!
Where is he?
NK!
Go!
You really came back to life just so you could
throw a tantrum, you stupid Cancer Cell?
Die!
Did I get him?
So, you fell for it!
He's nothing but a puppet!
Look at all the effort you had
to put in against a mere doll.
Do you know what you've gotten
yourselves into, Immune Cells?
Where the heck is that voice coming from?
I'm so thrilled!
It's the trio from before, right?
Cancer Cell!
Cancer Cells.
Cells that multiply uncontrollably
due to a genetic abnormality.
They overstep the boundaries with neighboring
cells in a process called "Infiltration."
It's been a long time, huh?
NK Cell...
Killer T, now Memory T Cell...
Lastly...
...Neutrophil...
This just might be what they call fate, huh?
For the three of you from that day
to saunter right toward me.
Now then, which of us, me or you three,
is on the side of justice?
Let's settle it once and for all.
Here he comes!
Die! Die!
NK!
I'll take care of the preview today!
Outta my way! I'm doing it!
Next episode of Cells at Work!!...
..."Cancer Cell II (Part I)"!
Hey, butt out, will you?
Shut up, loner!
Hey, be nice, you guys.