I wonder what's wrong.
Since he had had that talk with NK, things seem kind of tense.
Not looking good.
It's gone to ruin, all right.
I-I can't breathe!
This is toxic gas from the harmful bacteria that live in the intestines.
"Toxic gas"?
So, his friends are all here?
Yeah. There are up to a hundred trillion bacteria in the intestines, they say.
Then, we're sure to find them, right?
Yeah.
That'll be a relief.
He doesn't sound the least bit relieved.
Look, you two, I don't care what you do as long as you're quiet.
I don't want him to know we're on the move.
Now, I've fought with him once in the past.
And I'm going to use that experience today to head to the front lines as a Memory T Cell
and finish off the enemy!
U-Um, I just have a simple question.
Who's this guy you keep mentioning?
A Cancer Cell.
C-Cancer Cell?
Are you okay, Platelet?
Yes! I'm fine!
Everyone! Watch out, okay?
I can't see in front of me!
It looks like he's meeting us head-on this time.
Where is he?
You really came back to life just so you could throw a tantrum, you stupid Cancer Cell?
Die!
Did I get him?
So, you fell for it! He's nothing but a puppet!
Look at all the effort you had to put in against a mere doll.
Do you know what you've gotten yourselves into, Immune Cells?
I'm so thrilled!
It's the trio from before, right?
Cancer Cell!
It's been a long time, huh?
This just might be what they call fate, huh?
For the three of you from that day to saunter right toward me.
Now then, which of us, me or you three, is on the side of justice?
Let's settle it once and for all.
Here he comes!
Die! Die!
NK!
You really are a one-trick pony when it comes to attacking!
You saved us, NK!
Hey! You can gloat after you've untied us!
Now then... Boy, would you mind telling me something?
Why'd you come back to life when you knew you'd only be killed?
Don't tell me you actually thought you could win this time!
This is my second time battling you!
Your tactics are a little too exposed for you to be picking a fight with me, you know.
It's not that I want to pick a fight with you.
It's just that I've found what it is I have to do.
And I wanted you three to bear witness.
Surprised? These are all the same as that puppet you just saw.
They're all fragments of my tissue.
You can stab them with your sword, but they won't die.
They'll keep moving forever.
There isn't a thing that you can do. Just resign yourselves to being my captives.
Behind you, NK!
Over by you, too, Neutrophil!
Who do you think you're dealing with?
I'm Memory T Cell, and I've seen every one of your attacks!
Memory T Cell...
I see.
Meaning you're not quite the same guy you were before?
You can't escape!
Right now, I can foresee your every next move!
Right there!
Kindly cease your attacks.
Those are not the appropriate responses.
He is not an enemy from the outside world.
He was born of this body.
He's a cell just like us.
I will not allow any attacks on the body itself.
R-Regulatory T Cell...
Regulatory T Cells.
They control the activity of T Cells to prevent them from triggering anomalous immune responses.
Wh-Why...
...would you...
No good! Memory T!
Watch your back!
N-Neutrophil!
...146, where are you? Come in!
1146! Where are you?
Just as I thought.
Come in, 1146! Come in—
I knew you'd protect him. I was sure you would.
Let's have a nice, long chat... instead of killing each other.
Okay?
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Are those germs still behind us?
I'm not sure!
Just keep running!
Nyuuu!
We're going to keep our handkerchiefs pressed to our mouths and run low to the ground!
Okay!
It looks like the intestine is in even worse shape than before.
Big Sister Red Blood Cell...
What is it?
You see, you see... I don't think we can take this path.
See? Look!
You can't come this way!
The bacteria's invaded the area up ahead!
What?
Take another route and run as fast as you can!
R-Right!
I'm so scared...
Big Sister Red Blood Cell!
We're going to be fine, Backward Cap.
The Platelets seem really anxious.
I have to be their rock now!
You guys, we're going to run at top speed, okay?
Okay!
NK! Memory T!
Cancer Cell!
Memory T!
Let me out of here, Cancer Cell!
Wasn't I the one you wanted to kill?
If you have a grudge against me, then I'll take you on!
That won't do, White Blood Cell.
You shouldn't fly off the handle when you're all banged up.
You need to value your own life more.
If you agree to what I'm about to say, I'll let you out of there right away.
Since I'm sure it's tearing you apart to be locked up and helpless.
Regulatory T Cell, open this door, will you?
I'll do it! I'll kill this Cancer Cell! So please!
Kill? I can't open that door if you're going to kill him.
As he's in no way an external enemy.
Regulatory T Cell's role.
Regulatory T Cells are responsible for reining in the activity of Immune Cells,
preventing them from attacking the body's
own tissues or cells that are beneficial to the body.
In this case, as the Cancer Cell originated from this body,
instead of recognizing him as a foreign substance, a non-self cell,
she is trying to suppress the Immune Cells' attacks.
It's not like she's betraying you guys.
This is that lady's job, I hear.
Cancer Cell, I'm gonna kill—
You mustn't...
...ever attack other cells.
Isn't this amusing?
You normal cells are all so dead serious.
And yet, despite being dead serious...
White Blood Cell...
...you rescued that ordinary cell and those Lactic Acid Bacteria, didn't you?
About that... The only reason I didn't kill them
was because those bacteria weren't toxic to this body! That's all!
Sure. I get that, all right.
But the thing is, I've changed my mind somewhat. It got me thinking.
Lives that are necessary and lives that are not...
Why does such a distinction have to made at all?
When it's so tragic for us to be taking lives or being robbed of our lives,
why do we have to keep repeating that cycle over and over again?
What do you think? Have you ever had a thought like that?
It's for the sake of this body!
Because it's necessary! That's why we die and kill!
That's what I thought you'd say.
Okay, then let's take it a bit further.
Which is more important?
The lives of trillions of cells?
Or this body's one life?
We cells are killed, burn with hatred for each other and are sacrificed
all so that this body can go on living.
Those of us who get killed, and you guys, the ones who kill... We've all suffered so much.
So, how about a world where we cells don't have to kill or be killed at all?
Even if it's a world gone mad, approaching death...
If it's to make that world a reality even for a split second...
...don't you think we'd be justified in sacrificing the life of this body?
I won't let you! No way will I ever let you do such a thing!
Let me out of here, Cancer Cell!
I'll kill you! You're horrendously wrong, but I'll set you straight!
If this body dies, that means that all of us cells will die with it, too!
Sure, we'll die.
But we'll die after we've been liberated.
And it's my job to make that happen.
There's nothing wrong about that at all.
There's no way you could pull that off—
Oh, I can pull it off.
Regulatory T Cell is siding with me. Not to mention...
...this place, as well.
Th-Those fumes are...
...harmful bacteria...
...toxins!
When the new world is completed...
...then let's be friends, all right, White Blood Cell, you kindhearted assassin?
Stop!
Don't do it, Cancer Cell!
NK! Memory T! Regulatory T Cell! Are you all right?
Y-Yeah!
So, you're more worried about your friends than yourself?
You know, that's what I like about you along with all the contradictions you bear.
Even though you can only live for someone else's sake,
you were born a cell who can do nothing but kill others.
Watching you, I feel such pity and impatience.
And it's so entertaining.
How dare you!
I'm sick of all your yammering, you annoying little punk!
Cancer Cell, I'm gonna kill—
You mustn't...
...ever attack other cells.
Do you realize you've been repeating the same conversation over and over?
What are you, a moron?
Sh-Shut the cell up!
As if... I had time...
...to think... of different lines... every single time!
I totally agree.
In the first place...
...is that the only move you've got, pounding him head-on?
Can you at least try a different move for once, you idiot?
Shut up! This is how I've always been, moron!
That's right.
This is how you've always been.
Tactics were never your strong suit.
Easily swayed by your emotions, unable to thrive on victory,
and unable to use defeat as a stepping-stone...
You will never be able to defeat me like that.
It's futile to even struggle.
Just let it go and cease your attacks.
Nyuuu!
W-We're surrounded! What should I do?
Lactic acid bacteria.
Good bacteria that work to support the health of the human body.
They have a variety of features.
It's all right, Lactic Acid Bacterium!
I'll p-protect—
Huh! This cell just said he's going to protect that lactic acid bacterium!
That's pretty funny, you know.
Harmful bacteria.
Pathogenic E. coli, Staphylococci, Clostridium and the like
cause proteins to degrade and produce toxic by-products.
Why don't we test you to see if you can really protect it?
I wonder if you can withstand this.
The Harmful Bacteria Toxic Attack!
Nyuuu!
The toxicity of harmful bacteria.
Toxic effects of harmful bacteria
include intestinal putrefaction, production of toxins and carcinogens.
A host of deleterious effects to the human body can ensue, such as a weakened immune system,
foul-smelling stools and gas, and diarrhea or constipation.
My legs!
Nyuuu!
Show us a good time, Cell boy!
We came all this way to this side of the intestinal wall
only to find it duller than we thought, so it's been a real gut punch for us!
We're going to torment you every which way, so be sure to show us some juicy reactions!
Nyuuu! Nyu-nyuuu!
Nyuuu!
What kind of a lame attack is this?
Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Nyuuu!
Huh! You miserable good bacteria runt...
You're a germ, and yet you're sucking up to a cell?
If you dare turn on us, I'll obliterate you first!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Stay away, Lactic Acid Bacterium! Just run away as far as you can!
Nyuuu?
Don't worry about me! Just run and save yourself! Hurry!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
You dummy! Go now!
Hey, he's...
Get out of here now! I said go!
Nyuuu...
Get out of my sight!
Nyuuu!
Huh! Now that was one lame farce you made us watch.
Sorry that you were the only one who got such a sad goodbye.
But it's all right. As long as you can go on living, that's enough.
Grow up to be a strong, fine lactic acid bacterium, okay?
Now then, are you ready?
Time for us to have some fun!
Nyuuu!
I-It seems like you've really got your hands full, White Blood Cell!
Our battle has hardly even begun yet!
Next episode of Cells at Work!!...
..."Cancer Cell II (Part II)"!
Who was that just now?
Target sighted!