Nyuuu!
Come back here!
Cell boy!
Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium!
If he reaches an Immune Cell who can see that he's good bacteria, he'll be fine.
But if he gets dealt with as a mere foreign substance,
then it would be out of my hands.
Sorry.
No way.
That little guy... That little guy must've given it all for this this body, too! I know it!
Why would you kill someone like that?
You Immune Cells are jerks!
That's...
That's my...
That's our...
It's our job, that's why.
Long time no see.
NK Cell!
Here I am, taking my job seriously,
and knowingly or not, you utter something I can't just ignore.
Do you need to be schooled, perhaps?
If it wasn't for us Immune Cells,
the rest of you cells would be killed off by the germs, all right?
And by the way, I'm an NK Cell.
A Lymphocyte who can kill off any cell at her own discretion.
You need to watch your mouth, Cell boy.
Back off, NK!
I don't believe you, either, Neutrophil!
What are you doing, acting all buddy-buddy?
I-I'm not acting buddy-buddy at all!
This person's beyond ferocious! Are all Immune Cells like her?
Lactic Acid Bacterium, please just stay safe!
"Cytokines."
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu? Nyuuu?
Hey, good morning! I see you're awake...
Nyuuu?
...little Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
I found you passed out in the gutter outside, you know.
Nyuuu?
I don't know what happened to you, but you should rest up here for a bit.
Want a cookie?
Nyuuu!
I'm Dendritic Cell. Nice to meet you.
I just baked a big batch of these cookies. You can take your time eating them, okay?
Nyuuu!
Hey!
Where are you?
Wait for me, Lactic Acid Bacterium!
I'm coming to save you now!
Where are you?
Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Dammit!
I don't even have a clue!
What should I do?
I'm never going to find him, am I?
Oh my!
Are you looking for something?
Would you like us to help you find it?
Th-Th-Th-That won't be necessary!
Are you sure?
You seemed to be at a loss, so...
We're sorry we couldn't be of use to you.
Good day!
Let's go! Let's go!
Thank you for your hard work.
Hey! By the way, what are you two looking for?
Uh, nothing special, really.
Oh?
You sure seem to be searching pretty frantically to me.
Hey! Where are you?
Huh? Did you call?
Oh, pardon me. Looks like you've got the wrong guy.
Hey, Cell boy... Try not to be conspicuous while NK's around!
But I have to find him as soon as possible!
Never mind that, NK. What were you doing there yourself?
Well, let's just say I was looking for something, too.
You, looking for something?
Uh, an influenza virus has been detected near the small intestine.
Beware of the risk of being infected with influenza!
All Immune Cells in the area, please head to the site immediately!
Lightweights... At a time like this...
NK, what is it that you're looking for?
That red thing there!
Found you, Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Hold up! That's—
Kishaaa!
I-It's a virus-infected cell!
The influenza virus.
The virus responsible for the infectious disease influenza.
Falls into three main categories, A, B and C.
Causes symptoms, such as fevers over 100 degrees,
headaches, joint pain and muscle cramping.
I don't have time to fool around with you right now!
What the...
I-It's so strong!
Th-There's something really strange about them!
We came to help out!
Eat this, damn virus!
Take this!
All right! That should do it!
What the...
Memory Cell?
My heart just—
Memory Cell, what's wrong?
No good! It's the end of the world!
Everyone, run for your lives! We were utterly powerless!
Just as the stars will one day explode and dissolve into the darkness of outer space—
In a nutshell!
B Cell, we have no chance against that influenza virus!
Take a good look! Just look at him!
Look at that virus's head!
Those ominous points on his head!
That's a different type of virus!
Antigenic shift in influenza.
As influenza is prone to mutation, the nature of the antigen changes every year.
This is why it can't always be blocked by acquired immunity.
Our normal attacks aren't going to work on them!
Huh?
For real?
This world is doomed!
Nyuuu...
Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium?
Want some more cookies?
Nyuu... Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
And in return, if you don't mind...
...there's a favor I'd like to ask of you.
Nyuuu?
I-Influenza's something the body catches now and then, right? Is it that scary?
Yeah.
In its normal form, we'd have a chance against it,
but it's a lot different if it's gone through an antigenic shift!
We don't have a single clue about that one! Not a shred of data!
Even so, we can't just let them have their way...
...or the virus-infected cells could multiply like crazy!
Hey! The spores are gathering!
Oh crap! This is going to be hit-or-miss, but here goes!
How do you like this?
No good! It's not working!
Let's head into the tunnel for now!
White Blood Cell!
All right, now's your chance! Make a run for it!
O-Okay!
White Blood Cell!
Outta my way, Ordinary Cell!
I've got my hands full here!
It dodged that?
In that case...
These things...
I've never seen moves like that!
And they're crazy fast!
What's the problem, NK?
Neutrophil and I kill infected cells, too, but aren't you the pro among us?
They're dodging all of your attacks!
Sh-Shut up, will you? I-I'm not losing to a mere influenza virus!
N-NK?
Wh-What the...
What the heck are they doing?
The end is here!
Not good! They're heading this way!
Wh-What?
Are they bringing on a stomachache?
Run!
Or you'll get dragged into it!
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium!
Lactic Acid—
Protect him with your life!
White Blood Cell!
Nyuuu!
Thank goodness you're okay!
Thank you, White Blood Cell!
NK! You can't take them on in close combat now!
Distance yourself!
Damn... Why can't I... kill those low-level scrubs?
I'm done.
What's gotten into you, NK? You're the linchpin of our virus-infected cell suppression strategy!
NK, don't tell me you're...
...weakened by stress!
Are you in a slump?
I'm a natural-born assassin, and yet...
Immunity and stress.
Under stress, Lymphocyte activity becomes sluggish and immunity plummets.
Hey, NK, c'mon!
Who am I anyway? Seriously, I've had enough.
NK! Snap out of it!
I can't.
Who's going to stop these guys, then?
When we met up earlier,
I was trying to stand up for you because Cell boy was ranting at you.
But you just got mad at me, Neutrophil!
I-Is that right? M-My bad, NK! Thanks!
NK, don't ever lose confidence in yourself!
We're pros! We've got skills that we trained hard to master!
If we join forces, we can beat any enemy!
Get yourself motivated! Get up! Get up and run!
What's wrong? Are you motivated now—
N-NK, ma'am...
Whatever is the matter?
I'll kill anyone who saw it! I'll kill anyone who saw it!
Who the cell had the nerve to unearth this?
NK, are you activated now?
How on earth?
Hey, thanks a lot, Lactic Acid Bacterium.
Nyuuu?
Thanks to all these polysaccharides you produced.
Sorry.
Nyu-nyuuu!
For the first time in a long time...
...I've been activated!
How lactic acid bacteria works.
Some lactic acid bacteria
produce polysaccharides which modulate the immune system.
These immunomodulatory polysaccharides are said to assist in activating Dendritic Cells.
Good day, everyone!
D-Dendritic Cell? Why are you dressed like that?
Hey, the stomachache's getting closer! Let's get out of here!
Everyone! Our enemy today...
...is unbelievably strong, right?
Therefore, I'll be glad to support you from the shadows today!
Kindly take a look at the photos I've handed out!
Please gaze upon your past selves and remember from whence you came!
The truth is, I'd rather not do it this way. You know, stoop to blackmail.
Then, don't do it!
It's just that... You know, it'll motivate you to try harder this way.
The data doesn't lie!
So, let me be the first...
...to work even harder than usual, all right?
Cytokines.
The blanket term for physiologically active proteins
secreted by cells to stimulate other cells.
H-Hold up a second, Dendritic Cell! Don't go any farther—
We'll give it our all! We'll give it our all for sure even without those!
I've already been activated! Give me a break!
All right, everyone! Let's get cracking, all bright-eyed and bushy-tailed now!
Immunity boost.
When Dendritic Cells are activated, they are thought to boost NK activation
and produce antibodies against certain viruses through the production of cytokines.
Nooooo!
Oh my, how lovely.
Everyone's going to have a field day with these!
Are you kidding me?
Wh-What's this? What's this? What's this? What's this? What's this?
B-B-Black History!
Universe!
I'm on fire!
Look how motivated everyone is!
All right.
Let's join in!
Wh-Wh-What the cell is this?
N-No way is this me!
Who the cell is this immature Thymocyte kid who's a dead ringer for me?
Approved! Approved! Approved!
I see.
So, they were all able to fight like that because you activated Dendritic Cell.
That's right. Thanks to all the polysaccharides he produced.
Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium,
it's all thanks to you that they were able to drive out the influenza virus.
Nyuuu!
You're so tiny, and yet you're so amazing!
Nyu-nyuuu!
You're way better than me.
I mean, look at me. I dropped you in the waterway
and got blasted away by the stomachache.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Sorry I put you in danger like that.
Nyuuu?
It looks like someone will be coming to pick you up.
Oh, right.
See? Here they are!
Nyu-nyuuu!
Your friends!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
I didn't get to spend much time with you,
but this is goodbye.
Nyuuu...
Take care of yourself, okay?
Nyu-nyuuu!
So, you're down to one now?
I'll take that one to his friends for you.
Oh...
Right.
Hey, White Blood Cell...
I'm sorry I called you a jerk back at the waterway.
I know I said some horrible things.
Even though you were helping us out.
When I got blasted away by the stomachache,
I was so happy that you caught the lactic acid bacterium.
Thanks.
No, I'm the one who should be apologizing to you for scaring you,
for not notifying my friends,
for not being able to help you.
Sorry.
It's okay!
Also... there's no need to think you made me go along with you.
After all, I actually enjoyed myself a lot this time—
All right! I'm going to go apologize to everyone!
All you Immune Cells! Sorry, I had no idea!
Hold up, Cell boy!
Who knew you were being blackmailed by embarrassing photos to make you work harder?
Especially you, NK—
I don't know what you're talking about!
Just let her be, all right?
A-Anyway, let me return your last bacterium.
Oh, okay.
Wait here for a second. I'm going to go talk to NK.
Remember, it's all over if they find that one.
R-Right, I forgot!
I'll be right back!
Okay!
It's only you now, huh?
Nyuuu!
Are you lonely?
It's going to be all right.
I'll see to it that you're taken to your friends, too.
Nyuuu!
I'll kill that stupid leaf head!
No, that's not it!
Why am I so mentally weak?
NK!
Do you have a minute?
Uh, I'm just telling you because it's all over now.
It was that lactic acid bacterium that we were searching for.
We were keeping it hidden because we wanted to return it to its friends.
Oh really?
I totally don't give a hoot.
It must be fun to have such a peaceful life.
Anyway, NK...
What was it that you were searching for?
Oh, so that's where this is going?
Fine. It's not like it has nothing to do with you, so I'll tell you.
Take this as a warning, too.
Neutrophil, no matter who the enemy is,
it's in your best interest not to think twice before killing it.
You know that the data on all the cells we kill is stored as antibody data, right?
And you also know that as long as they have that data, cells can replicate, don't you?
Yeah.
A certain cell's antibody data has been leaked.
What?
Along with the genetic data included in those records.
That cell's already acquired a physical form somewhere inside this body.
You remember, don't you?
The one who swore to come back to life and kill you...
And now I'm gonna die without leaving my mark on this world!
Why was I ever born in the first place?
That's who I'm searching for.
Pretty sweet to have your own body!
Now I can finally see you.
At last.
I can't wait.
You see, you see...
They say there are germs called "hard candy bacteria" in the large intestine!
Wait, I think you mean "harmful bacteria," right?
Next episode of Cells at Work!!, "Harmful Bacteria."
Work hard every day!