egao purasu issho nara
If we stand hand in hand and put on a smile
namida niji ni naru
Every tear will be filled with light
ureshii kimochi afureru hi wa
On the days when we overflow with happiness
kono kodou hayaku naru
Our pulse hurries up to match the pace
sukoshizutsu kawatteku hibi
Though the world marches on and changes bit by bit
issho ni kakeashi de ikou
If we're together, we can take it on
meguritsuzukeru sekai de
Let's go run ahead with all our energy
asu no tobira hirakou yo
All the way to the door to a new dawn
Hello Precious Days
Hello, precious days
Lucky, Lucky Days
Lucky, lucky days
Fight, Fight, asu omoi todokeyou
Fight on, fight on, 'til we reach our goal, give it our all
Hello Special Days
Hello, special days
Happy, Happy Days
Happy, happy days
Fight, Fight uchuu no sugata tsutaete ikou
Fight on, fight on, all that we ever do gives our world its form
egao purasu issho nara
If we stand hand in hand and put on a smile
namida niji ni naru
Every tear will be filled with light
onaji toki arukou With Me
And then when we do, would you come with me?
With Me
With me