"Acquired Immunity."
What's this?
What are all these images I'm seeing?
They're heading this way!
They just keep flowing
right into my mind!
Mump...
What's wrong with you, Memory Cell?
M-Meteorite shower, people fighting, a messenger from the outside world...
Huh?
What were those images I just saw?
Why would I have such a gorefest of a dream
when I'm not even a phagocyte?
It shouldn't happen!
The whole thing felt so abnormal.
Did I envision the moment the world will end?
If that's the case, then was that a vision of the future?
And that dream... Could it be...
Memory?
It's not just that I've committed
all past antigen battles to memory...
...now I have the ability to see the future, too?
Memory!
If that's true, then when that virus shows up,
the world will come to an end!
Do you hear me, Memory?
Enough with the mumbo jumbo!
Just get on with recording the antigen data, will you?
Whether or not I can put up a fight
all depends on your knowledge, okay?
A viral infection has just been detected in the parotid gland.
All immune cells in the area,
please head to the site immediately.
Come on, let's go! If it's a known antigen,
we have to mow them down with antibodies!
Come on, time to get to work!
R-Right.
See? It's that thing hiding in the shadows!
I wonder what that one is. This is so weird.
Mump.
What is that thing? That's one strange virus.
Memory, is it in your records?
Huh? Memory?
Get a hold of yourself!
Memory!
It's not like the world's definitely going to end just yet!
Use your gift of second sight to find a solution!
Come to me.
Come to me!
Mump!
Wait a sec!
Huh?
Antigen sighted!
Mump!
Die!
Hey, thanks, Neutrophil.
Sure. Long time no see, B Cell and Memory Cell.
Don't leave me behind!
Come to me, premonition! Come to me! Come to me!
What happened to my third eye? Open up!
Hey, is something wrong, Memory Cell?
Never mind. We'll deal with all this,
so you guys go on ahead.
Mump!
Wha...
Whaaat?
Oh my! Oh my!
Th-These guys are multiplying like crazy now!
I don't believe it! All that fighting that I foresaw is really happening now!
Sure, it seems somewhat different from what I saw with my second sight,
but does this mean that my gift is the real deal?
Meaning that the fate of this world is—
Hey, there you are, B Cell!
Hurry up and make some antibodies to save us!
This virus is no joke!
Hold on a second. I can't make antibodies without any data on the antigens.
Someone has to present the antigen first.
Okay then, forget the antibodies! Just take those guys out!
Well, I may be a type of white blood cell,
but I don't do phagocytosis.
I specialize in antibody attacks, so—
Oh, come on! Figure something out, useless!
Wh-What did you call me?
I'm the only one who can save the world!
Focus! Clear your mind!
A bizarre virus... A battle... Something...
Something's about to come raining down, I think.
I have no idea! Come on! My miracle second sight power!
Whoa! What are you doing, Memory? Hey!
Mump!
Take this!
Thanks for saving us!
Will that do?
I'll go present the antigen to
the commander helper T cell, then.
Take care, everyone!
Roger that! We're counting on you!
Counting on you!
Once the antigen's presented, we'll be saved.
But can we hold out until then?
Come on! Help me look, Memory!
We'll make do with a similar-looking virus!
Can't you think of anything?
Don't talk to me, B Cell! The future... I'm about to get a glimpse of the future!
All this talk about the future when we're in a crisis...
Never mind the future! Remember the past, will you?
Hey...
That's right.
It happened all too suddenly.
From out of the distant sky,
way beyond anyone's reach,
a colossal tube appeared.
And then, a flood of spheres sealed by powers from another world came spilling out.
Hey, there's something inside! Inside those capsules!
What are these things? They're weak as hell!
You're right, totally weak! Could they be any weaker?
Mump!
Such pushovers. I wonder what their deal is.
Who knows?
I guess we should stick to protocol
and have someone present the antigen
and preserve the data sample.
Leave it to me.
Please record the antigen data, alright, Memory Cell?
Oh! Will do!
So, that wasn't me seeing the future,
but rather images from the past that I was seeing?
Vaccination.
A preemptive injection of a weakened pathogen
used to acquire immunity to an antigen
as a preventative measure
to develop protection against a particular disease.
The antigenic substance that is administered is called a "vaccine".
Mump!
Here they come! They're going to try to smother us all at once!
Wh-What's going on?
Hey, you guys...
Thanks for waiting.
The system will now launch.
Self-check, okay. Initiating deployment protocol.
Target identified.
Antigens identified. Targets locked-on.
Energy charge complete.
Eat this, you dirty virus! This is...
...the power of acquired immunity!
Acquired immunity.
Immunity acquired by infection or vaccination after birth.
And so, thanks to the power of acquired immunity,
the pathogens soon vanished without a trace.
Wow, that only took a second!
And without antigen presentation, too!
Way to go, B Cell!
Good ol' antibodies!
Well, he was able to make those antibodies without the antigen presentation
thanks to my memories, you know.
What are you talking about? Jeez! In the first place, it was you who—
Oh, hey! Never mind that!
There already was an entry on today's virus, listing it as an antigen,
but you were going on and on
about some prophecy, and you just forgot. That was the problem!
What's going on here?
The thing is, this guy really dropped the ball today!
Hey, um, h-hey, hey, B Cell...
Just take a look at this.
Mumps virus.
The virus that causes epidemic parotitis.
Characterized by swelling
of one or both parotid glands, causing difficulty in swallowing.
This is why epidemic parotitis
is also known as the "mumps",
the plural form of "mump", meaning "grimace".
I mean, look how thorough your records are!
Shouldn't we feel ridiculous? After all that toil!
Keep it in your head, for goodness sake!
Forget this ever happened, okay?
Huh? Should I have kept my mouth shut?
Where's the virus?
It seems it's over already.
Man, I'm beat.
"Peyer's Patch."
Here's the next batch!
Lactose, sucrose, maltose!
Right!
So, this is the small intestine!
This is where they process all the nutrients, right?
Hey, what a bustling, pleasant place this is, huh?
Thank you so much for showing us around!
I have absolutely no clue about this area!
Don't mention it. You're welcome.
This is my first time here too,
but I learned all about the small intestine
during my erythroblast days.
Didn't anyone teach you, Sis?
I-I know! Why don't I go get us some tea?
I'll only be a minute!
Oh, thanks so much!
Hey, neutrophil! You've sure got guts.
Here we are in the intestines, a single membrane away from 100 trillion teeming bacteria,
and you're totally mellowing out.
Let me remind you, this isn't a vacation spot
for you nonchalant cells to zone out in!
It's a battleground where we immune cells
lock eyes with the germs!
Killer T...
I never knew you neutrophils were this complacent.
If you don't get your act together,
you and your friends will end up massacred, game over.
I'm not going to let that happen.
What's that? You've got a problem?
You're the one to blame.
I was only showing some new red blood cells around
to help them do their jobs.
That's what I mean! Enough with the handholding!
Killing the enemy is the only thing that should be on your mind!
H-Hey, hey, both of you...
All I want to know is, will you be able to respond in an emergency if you're so laid-back?
What if, even as we speak,
there were germs on the...
...attack.
This isn't the usual colony of intestinal bacteria!
We're being attacked by every last germ in these nutrients!
This is No. 1146! Bacteria that multiplied
in the small intestine at D6-18 has landed!
The surrounding tissue is being destroyed! Requesting immediate backup!
Killer T...
Huh?
We'll pick this up again later.
Give us a hand if it comes to that.
Right.
The toxic gas from that bacteria
is endangering the surrounding cells!
If we don't stop them, it'll generate carcinogenic metabolites!
We have to eliminate them right away!
I'd like to see you try it, white blood cell.
Of course...
...if you care at all about this intestinal epithelial cell,
your only option is to do whatever we campylobacters say!
Campylobacter.
One of the types of bacteria that causes infectious enteritis,
triggering fevers, diarrhea, and stomach pain.
Wha... A hostage? That's so low!
Help me!
It's not like we haven't thought this through.
After all, you murdered so many of our friends.
Because your duty is to protect the lives
of all the normal cells, am I right?
Alright, we shouldn't be lounging around here,
or you might catch us off-guard.
We'll be standing by inside the intestinal tract.
Try and catch us if you can, white blood cells!
Dammit!
We can't exit this tissue!
Hold up, Campylobacter!
Give us back that hostage! What are your demands?
We want you to make these intestines
a bit more comfortable.
For us campylobacters, that is.
You'll deliver nutrients to us first
and eliminate all germs that get in the way!
And you white blood cells will perform for us every day on the other side of that membrane
to keep us entertained.
Easy as pie!
Also, you'll provide us with three meals and a nap per day,
and prime real estate in a quiet location
commanding a fine view
where we can build our own colony!
We're going to build a paradise of campylobacters,
by campylobacters, and for campylobacters!
After which, for the sake of maintaining order in perpetuity and for all eternity...
Alright, fine.
We'll accept your terms.
Once we've done that— What? No way! You accept?
Yippee!
What the...
Alright! In that case, we'll release the hostage, but first, do as I say!
Think about what you've done!
You bastards slaughtered scores of our friends! Dance some kind of jig!
We have no choice! Dance!
Now pulverize each other!
Wh-What the cell is that moron doing?
I always knew he was a moron,
but who would've known he was this stupid?
W-We did as you asked.
Alright, then, let the hostage go!
Now that you're in such a weakened state,
you probably couldn't catch me if I invaded the tissue.
What? Don't tell me you're...
It'd be too pathetic if you died because you turned on each other.
Why don't I just finish you off myself?
Wait, Campylobacter! That's not what we agreed on! Let the hostage—
What do I care? Die!
You utter fool!
They were never going to release the hostage!
How can you not see that?
Chief...
Just look at you!
You really underestimated the power of a germ!
Bye now!
Come back here! You're not heading that way!
Jeez, the germ just took off with the hostage!
Damn, I can't even watch this.
You stupid nonchalant cell...
Talk about pesky!
You still have enough strength left to chase after me?
Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch!
Are you okay,
No. 1146?
This is bad! Look at us! We're so close to
that spot that's super-easy to infiltrate!
There's no villi there, so it's like
an easy-access entrance for bacteria!
You idiot! Keep your voice down about that stuff!
Hey! That is...
Shush! We can't let them find out!
My bad!
They're in an uproar about something.
Hey, do you know what they're talking about?
W-Well, that would be... um...
Well, if I told you...
...would you at least spare my life?
Sure, I can do that.
Don't do it, Intestinal Epithelial Cell!
You see, up ahead, there's a spot where both villi and membranes are sparse.
Anything but that! Just don't mention that to them!
And if I may say so myself, it's about as airtight as a sieve.
So, I imagine it would be easily infiltrated by you bacteria.
By any chance, would you be talking about...
...this place right here?
Uh-oh! We're doomed! They found it!
Um, what should I do now?
Shut up! I have no more use for you!
Yippee! Follow me, you guys! We've invaded the tissues!
From here on in, we'll have unlimited food
and a warm place to sleep!
And we'll never have to worry about earning our keep again!
Woo-hoo! Nutrients!
Lucky us! Look how much there is!
Let's start gorging ourselves and dividing like crazy!
Welcome.
What'll it be for you, sir?
What do you mean, what'll it be?
I'm a bacterium! I want all of the food here!
Ah, you don't say.
Please, partake.
After all, this is more or less your Last Supper.
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest.
What are you talking about?
Oh, never mind! I'll just grab whatever—
Wha...
We thought you'd never get here, Campylobacter.
An immune cell? Wh-What are you doing here?
Wh-What good will it do to take us on alone?
It's punishment time.
To think that you couldn't see through all that blatant baiting...
Stooping to dirty tactics like taking a hostage...
Don't underestimate us neutrophils!
This is a piece of immune tissue within the small intestine
where we lure in stupid germs like you to massacre!
A Peyer's Patch!
Peyer's Patches.
A mass of immune tissue that can be found within the small intestine
in depressions between villi and areas without any.
They are filled with lymphatic nodules.
These patches play a crucial role in the intestinal immune system.
And I'm an M cell, the proprietor of this Peyer's Patch.
M cells.
Cells found on the surface of the Peyer's Patch
which trap bacterial and viral antigens.
The captured bacteria and viruses
are handed off to the dendritic cells
and presented as antigens.
You never caught on, but when you knocked us back, we signaled to our comrades
that we were going to lure you to the Peyer's Patch.
S-Signal?
That's right!
That was...
...an "M" for "M cell"!
Th-That's not fair!
Shut up! Like fair has anything to do with it!
Hey, that sure worked out!
Good job, getting him to fall for your trap!
I know I kept calling you a moron,
but you really do have a good head
on your shoulders. I had the wrong idea about you.
Killer T...
But from now on, try not to mellow out too much.
Try not to mellow out too much.
I seem to have forgotten something.
That white blood cell's taking forever, huh?
Just how long are we going to wait?
I wonder if he got lost.
Uh-oh!
I totally forgot to get the red blood cells their tea!
I take it back, he's a moron.
My receptor's picked something up!
White Blood Cell! There's a weird mask on the ground!
De-Dengue!
Next episode of Cells at Work!!...
..."Dengue Fever/Acne".
Work hard every day!