"H. Pylori."
There are virus-infected cells here, too!
We have a situation near the pharynx.
Immune Cells... are to head to the site immediately!
Target sighted!
Come on, come on, come on!
We're going to slaughter 'em all!
Die!
Don't let any get away!
And so, it's the same old, same old again today.
The Immune Cells come swooping in,
defeat the infected bad guys, and now the town is peaceful again.
And so, just like any other day,
we ordinary cells are stuck on the sidelines again.
What a drag!
I mean, those Immune guys just don't play fair!
The way they put on that whole superhero act when they're just a bunch of assassins...
And then, when we get attacked by viruses, they're like...
..."It's your own fault for not protecting yourselves!"
or "You should've done your homework!"
Jeez.
Just once in my life, if someone would say, "Thank you for rescuing me!"
What wouldn't I give to hear those words?
If only I was stronger!
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
G-G-Germs?
Oh man, I've stumbled upon something I shouldn't have! I've got to let the Immune Cells know!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Wh-What's wrong?
Nyuuu!
You can't get out of there?
You're germs! Don't beg a cell for help!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
What am I going to do?
I'll help you, but you'd better go back to where you came from, okay?
What, are you still babies?
That's it! You've got this!
You can do it! Almost there!
Nyuuu!
Look at those happy faces.
Hey, I just rescued some germs.
Oh man.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Hey, don't get attached to me! You guys are germs, aren't you?
Hey! Ordinary Cell there! What are you being so sneaky about?
N-N-N-N-Nothing! It's nothing!
I just kind of overate! I wasn't feeling well, so I decided to crouch here to rest!
Is that right? Take care, then!
Jeez, that was close! There's no telling what they would do if they spotted you.
Nyuuu!
Now, be good and go back to where you came from.
Nyuuu?
See ya.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Hey, stop following me, dammit!
I don't want to get yelled at, all right?
I'll pretend I never saw you, so try to make it back to—
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Nyuuu!
I went and brought them home.
Jeez, this is bad! I'm so going to get yelled at!
Wait, worst case, I could get killed, too!
My receptor's definitely picking something up,
so where are the antigens?
Hey, White Blood Cell!
Thank you for saving us earlier!
Sure.
Is something the matter?
No. I've been patrolling this area for antigens, and...
Not at home?
Hello? I've come to deliver your oxygen!
Ordinary Cell?
Nyuuu!
Dummies! Shush! Shush!
Keep it down, all right? If we're caught, they're going to kill you!
Hello? Cell boy? Are you in there?
No answer, huh?
Do you think maybe he was talking in his sleep?
Well, never mind.
I have to find those antigens first.
No, hold up!
Maybe the antigen's threatening Cell boy inside there,
and there's no way for him to call for help,
so he emitted that sound just now as a last resort?
If you call for help, you're dead!
Nyuuu!
I-It's all quiet out there now.
Are they gone?
All right.
I'm going to slip out now and take them back.
Hey, Cell boy! Are you okay? I'm coming to save you now!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
And what exactly...
...is your explanation for this?
W-Well, long story short, I rescued them, but then they got attached to me.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
And when I thought about them being killed, I couldn't turn my back on them.
I see.
I can see how it'd be hard to turn your back on them.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Oh? You're hungry?
I don't have anything for you.
I said, I have nothing. See?
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Cell boy...
I understand how you feel,
but I can't allow germs to multiply inside this body.
Once they multiply, germs go on to release toxins, harming the cells inside the body.
In some cases, this could trigger hemolysis which would destroy the Red Blood Cells
or take away their nutrients.
You understand, right?
I guess it would be cruel to do it before his eyes.
Thank you for your help in capturing the antigens.
Oh...
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
This is No. 4989!
We're battling germs in the stomach, and it's not looking good!
We need your backup right away!
Roger that! I'm on my way!
Cell boy, sorry, but I'm taking custody of these germs!
Ordinary Cell?
S-Sure, of course.
He's only doing his job.
Protecting us all is the Immune Cells' job, after all.
U-Uh...
Hey, wait, Ordinary Cell!
Sign this!
That's right! Run around in a frenzy!
What's going on?
Where's the enemy?
Hey, 1146!
Um, it's on the other side of that wall!
Pylori!
H. pylori.
Resistant to gastric acid.
Can trigger gastrointestinal diseases, causing ulcers and sometimes leading to stomach cancer.
It's a type of harmful bacteria, detrimental to the human body.
Officially known as "Helicobacter pylori."
H. pylori? Who would've thought?
There's nothing you cells can do to stop me!
We H. pylori have bodies that are tough as nails, so we can operate in gastric acid!
Unlike you lot!
It's like chaos here!
So, this is the front line, huh?
Nyuuu...
B-But it's not like we can go to him, you know! We'll get dissolved in that gastric acid!
I'll go!
I'll land a fatal blow on him before I get dissolved!
What? But 1146, if you do that, you'll die!
There's no way around it! It's for the sake of this body!
For the sake of this body...
That's right. It's for the sake of this body.
To die for someone else's sake... How cool is that?
For someone like me...
For a humble ordinary cell like me, that would be impossible.
How powerless am I anyway?
This world belongs to the H. pylori now!
Oh, crap! The stomach lining!
At least put this on! It's made of acid-resistant enamel!
It's crumbling!
Look out!
C-Cell boy!
Sorry. I'm nothing but an ordinary cell,
so I can't protect you like I should.
You guys are bacteria inside this body, so you're going to end up dead.
But you know what?
I would've saved you if I could.
Just remember that you did have somebody who cared about you.
Well, now, I've seen everything! A cell, protecting germs?
Hmm... I just know I've seen you somewhere before.
Are you all right?
Oh, never mind! I'm going to eliminate you all in one go!
Take this! Gastric Acid Hell!
Uh-oh!
Nyuuu!
Those germs opened up a hole, so now we have a pathway!
This is our chance to take over this—
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu!
Huh?
The other germs that happened to show up just got turned into slush!
Can you believe how powerful that was?
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
W-Wait! One's missing!
No way! So, I guess he's—
Nyuuu...
Hey, he's alive!
Wh-What's going on?
That germ's acting...
Wh-What was that? Did the H. pylori just take a hit from that germ's attack?
Grrr! I-Impossible! You actually dared to inflict a wound on me?
Huh? W-Wait, don't tell me you're...
...a lactic acid bacterium?
Nyuuu!
Lactic acid bacteria.
Rather than refer to a specific bacteria, it is the blanket term for germs
that produce lactic acid in massive quantities
by breaking down sugars to produce the energy necessary for growth.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Stop it!
I can't take this! My only option is to flee—
Oh no...
You finally came out from the sea of acid!
N-N-N-Now I've done it!
Nyuuu!
You pylo-ing scum...
Die!
Nyuuu!
Pylori!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
D-Did he just beat that huge H. pylori?
Wh-Wh-What's up with you guys?
Hey, don't jump on me! You're all covered in gastric acid! It's bad for me!
Hey, are those germs...
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Yeah. It looks like it.
Cell boy...
I'm so sorry!
After what just happened, I get it now...
...exactly what kind of germs those guys are.
Nyuuu!
Those germs...
...are good bacteria that work for the sake of this body.
Good bacteria.
The layperson's term for the bacteria found in the digestive system
that are beneficial for the human body's health.
Well-known examples include lactic acid and lactobacillus bifidus.
Some lactic acid bacteria are resistant to gastric acid
and can suppress the activation of H. pylori.
Nyuuu!
They must've entered this body along with food or something.
I've never seen them in an inactive state, so I didn't realize it at first.
All right, I have to get back to patrol duty.
Because bacteria might invade through that hole the H. pylori ripped open.
B-But what about these guys?
Hey, you want to go to your friends, don't you?
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
I can't go with you. I'll melt.
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu... Nyuuu...
Go on.
Nyuuu...
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Take care of yourself.
All right, Cell boy...
I'm about to tell you something that has nothing to do with you.
There are all kinds of types of lactic acid bacteria,
and I hear they all work with their friends near different digestive organs.
I'm heading out to patrol those areas now.
Wanna come along?
Yeah!
Hey!
So, there you are, Ordinary Cell!
I was wondering where you'd gone!
If you could just stamp that receipt...
...or your signature will do, too. Right here, please.
Sorry, I forgot all about that.
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Ordinary Cell, haven't you put on some weight since I last saw you?
Huh? Oh, yeah...
"Antigenic Shift."
All right, I'm heading this way.
Right.
Good work!
This is the small intestine.
Okay! Hoist up the microvilli from No. 1 through 10!
There are all sorts of stuff coming in again today.
Nice to get some balanced nutrition, huh?
Nyuuu!
So, this is the small intestine, huh?
I've never been to a place like this before! It's awesome!
Put those lactic acid bacteria away or they'll be spotted.
It looks like they're scooping something up with a huge net. What is that?
There are nutrients that got dissolved in the stomach on the other side of this wall.
It's here in the small intestine that they get absorbed into the body,
processed and turned into nutrients for you cells.
Hey, you're right! We eat that stuff all the time!
Wow!
Nyuuu!
But if they're from outside, doesn't that mean all kinds of substances get in? Like viruses?
Bad stuff like that isn't absorbed by mistake, right?
Most of it gets destroyed by gastric acid, so it's all good.
Still, there are other things, too, that can get tricky.
Whoa! What's all this?
What are we going to do with all this? Did you have to absorb this boatload of purines?
B-But, sir, we have no recourse against the mass production of purines.
Don't make excuses!
Listen, you know that uric acid is formed when the body breaks down purines!
And if there's an excess buildup of uric acid, sharp crystals will form, and that would mean major trouble!
Oh man, he's getting yelled out. Poor guy...
Yeah.
I'm telling you, it's like every other word out of your mouth is some excuse!
That's why you're no good!
Nyuuu...
Nyuuu!
Hey! Hey you, get back here!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Nyuuu!
Huh? Wh-What's that thing?
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
It's eating the purines!
Burp.
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Is it happy because it's eaten its fill?
Nyuuu?
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Wait! Huh? All they're doing is devouring the purines?
These guys are pretty docile, huh?
Hey, you're doing us a favor!
Here, eat up these purines, too!
Nyuuu!
Aren't they amazing? Watch them gobble it all up!
Smug!
I see.
So, this is what these lactic acid bacteria do?
Lactic acid bacteria coexist with cells in the body in various ways according to type.
These guys can make friends with all kinds of cells!
That's incredible!
I guess the small intestine might be the ideal place for those germs to live.
Yeah.
Hey!
Nyuuu?
Nyu-nyu-nyuuu!
Take care.
Well, who knew? Lactic acid bacteria really does a lot for the body, huh?
Do these guys totally rock or what?
Well, don't get too carried away, Cell boy.
They may be useful, but germs are germs.
If they ever start acting sketchy, I'm going to deal with them right away.
And one more thing. Whatever you do, don't ever let anyone see them.
If any of the other Immune Cells spot them, I—
Hey, check this out, will you?
Ta-da!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
A lactic acid bacterium in the hand and one on the head!
These guys are so fluffy and adorable!
Go ahead and pet them, White Blood Cell!
Huh? Germs nearby? My receptor!
Moron! Hide them! Do you want them to get killed?
Whoa! Don't yell at me!
Huh? There's nothing here.
Malfunction, I guess. This receptor of mine...
Wh-Whoa!
Nyuuu!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
The lactic acid bacterium!
Nyuuu!
Come back here!
Cell boy!
Nyuuu!
Lactic Acid Bacterium!
What should I do? It's too dangerous for him to be on his own!
I have to look for him!
But there's no telling where he'll end up inside this vast body.
I know! White Blood Cell, can you notify the other Immune Cells right now?
Tell them not to kill that lactic acid bacterium!
I'm sorry. I can't do that.
We Neutrophils are unable to present antigens.
I can't tell other Immune Cells not to attack him because he's good bacteria.
If he reaches an Immune Cell who can see that he's good bacteria, he'll be fine.
But if he gets dealt with as a mere foreign substance,
then it would be out of my hands.
Sorry.
No way.
Nyuuu?
I don't get it, White Blood Cell.
You know he's not a bad guy.
Right. Even still...
That little guy... That little guy must've given it all for this body, too! I know it!
Why would you kill someone like that?
You Immune Cells are jerks!
That's...
That's my...
That's our...
It's our job, that's why.
That voice just now...
Long time no see.
NK Cell!
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
What, you want to take part in the preview?
Hey! Sounds like it'll be fun!
Next episode of Cells at Work!!...
..."Cytokines."
Nyuuu! Nyuuu!
Please look forward to it!